itworldcanada.com 2014-05-02

# IT World Canada Inc. Online Privacy Statement | IT World Canada

**IT World Canada Inc. Online Privacy Statement**

Effective January 1, 2013

 **IT WORLD CANADA’S COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY**

This Online Privacy Statement is a simplified version of IT World Canada’s Privacy Policy. It is designed to inform you of our practices regarding collection, use, and disclosure of information you may provide via IT World Canada’s Web sites.

Our Privacy Policy follows the _Canadian Standards Association Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information_ and complies with federal and provincial privacy laws including the federal _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ (PIPEDA). A summary of the ten principles of fair information practices on which the Privacy Policy is based is included at the end of this Privacy Statement.

Please read this Privacy Statement completely before using or submitting information via this site.

 **PRIVACY QUESTIONS AND ACCESS**

ITWorldCanada.com is the Web site for IT World Canada Inc. and its online publications: _CanadianCIO, ComputerWorld Canada, ITBusiness.ca, Computer Dealer News and Direction Informatique._

This site is maintained by:  
IT World Canada  
302-55 Town Centre Court  
Scarborough, ON, M1P 4X4  
Phone: (416) 290-0240  
Fax: (416) 290-0238

If you have a question about this statement, contact IT World Canada’s Privacy Officer by mail at the above address, by phone at 416-290-0240 Ext 221, or email [privacy@itworldcanada.com](mailto:privacy@itworldcanada.com)

You can also contact us at this address if you have a question about IT World Canada’s handling of your information, if you wish to obtain a copy of information you have provided to us, or if you become aware that information you have provided is incorrect and would like us to correct it. Before we can provide information or correct any inaccuracies, however, we may ask you to verify your identity and other details that will help us to respond to your request. We will endeavor to respond within a reasonable timeframe.

 **CONSENT**  
By using an IT World Canada Web site, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Statement. Whenever you submit information via this site, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of that information, personal or otherwise, as described in this Privacy Statement.

 **SITE REGISTRATION**  
The Web site ITWorldCanada.com provides news, news analysis and other information primarily intended to support those engaged professionally in the development, support, management and strategic application of Information and Information Technology (I&IT) in a business environment.

IT World Canada does not charge a fee for visitors to access the site’s content; instead, as with many Web sites, revenue is generated through advertising and sponsorships. Our advertisers and sponsors have a reasonable expectation that visitors to the site are genuine and meet certain minimum qualifications in the field we serve. Much of the site’s content is, therefore, offered only to registered users. Information collected through the registration process is used by IT World Canada to verify the professional profile of visitors.

 **Cookies used in registration**  
As part of the registration process we use a browser feature called a “cookie”. A cookie is a piece of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your computer as a small text file. The cookie we send as part of the registration process allows the site to recognize that a visitor is a registered user and permit access to restricted sections of the site on future visits.

For a more detailed explanation of our use of cookies, please see the section, _Information We May Place Automatically On Your Computer’s Hard Drive_ , found later in this statement.

 **PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION**

We are committed to providing you with an Internet experience that respects and protects your personal privacy choices and concerns. Personally identifying information is collected by IT World Canada only when you specifically and knowingly provide it.

 **COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION**  
Beyond the site registration described previously, IT World Canada collects and uses your personal information primarily for the purpose of providing you with the products and services you have requested from us, including the delivery of the online publications _CanadianCIO, ComputerWorld Canada, ITBusiness.ca, Computer Dealer News and Direction Informatique_ and related content; delivery of electronic or direct-mailed newsletters; and, event registration confirmations, updates and other information related to IT World Canada products, events and seminars.

The information we collect is also used to communicate with you about your subscriptions and to provide you with information related to other IT World Canada and its sister IDG companies and the IDG Network publications and services.

All e-mails sent to subscribers clearly identify the source of the e-mail as IT World Canada, its publications or IDG.

Subscribers may elect not to receive e-mail from third parties when e-mail information is collected, and in response to any e-mail received. Subscribers may change their preferences at any time by e-mail to IT World Canada [circulation@itworldcanada.com](mailto:circulation@itworldcanada.com) or by calling the circulation department at (613) 475-3217

If you have indicated that you are interested in receiving offers or information from selected IT World Canada sponsors or advertisers, your personal information would also be used by IT World Canada to contact you or to send you e-mail materials and other mailings on their behalf. Your personal information is never shared with third parties. The information submitted by them is fully screened by IT World Canada and must, in our judgment, be of value to the IT Community. However, you always have the option to tell us not to send offers for other products or services.

If you enter a contest or participate in other promotional activities offered by IT World Canada, your personal information will be used to administer the promotion, including the use of your name and selected other information for the purposes of contacting, announcing and promoting the winners of the promotion.

IT World Canada may also contact you from time to time to conduct research and surveys in our ongoing effort to improve our product and service offerings, or to invite your editorial comments for articles being developed for publication.

IT World Canada will not release your personal information to a third party without your authorization unless required to by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or to comply with a legal process serviced on our Web site.

IT World Canada will only ask you to provide personal information that we need, when we need it. We will always explain why we need the information and what we intend to do with it.

We will seek your prior consent to the collection, use and disclosure of personally identifying information and you can refuse such consent. You may also withdraw your consent at a later time by giving us reasonable notice. We will notify you in advance of any change in our intent for the use or disclosure of your personally identifying information.

Your personal information will not be used for any other purpose without your consent.

 **DISCLOSURE**  
In order to effectively provide the products and services you have requested, IT World Canada may share your personal information with selected third parties who act on our behalf as suppliers or service providers. Examples include bonded mailing houses for processing and labeling items, including publications, prior to mailing; and, Canada Post and other distributors and carriers. We provide only the information required to perform the requested service. Information provided to third parties in these circumstances may only be used for the stated purpose. It is our practice to require third party suppliers to handle information in a manner consistent with IT World Canada’s policies.

In addition, the information collected to service your subscriptions may be made available — on IT World Canada’s premises only — for review by the Canadian Circulation Audit Bureau (CCAB), or another bona fide third-party auditing entity. The auditors may also contact randomly selected subscribers in order to verify that, as publishers, our distribution statements are accurate.

 **SUPPLEMENTING INFORMATION**  
From time to time we may supplement information you give us via our Web site with information we acquire from other sources, such as information to validate your address, or company information available through sources such as business directories. This is to help us maintain consistency and accuracy of the information we collect and to help us provide a better service.

 **SPONSORED WEBCASTS**

ITWorldCanada.com, via its affiliate ITworld.com, is a producer and host of sponsored Webcasts for a variety of companies. All data collected via a Webcast registration will be shared with those sponsors and is governed by the individual sponsor’s privacy policy and may be used by them for follow-up purposes. ITWorldCanada.com will have similar access to this data as the Webcast host, and may also use it to follow up with viewers regarding other information we have available.

In addition, your personally identifiable information may be gathered, processed or used by ITWorldCanada.com or its affiliate ITworld.com to authenticate you when you want to update your personal profile or to log on to select ITWorldCanada.com services; to support customer questions about the use of ITWorldCanada.com; to help you manage/modify your profile; to troubleshoot problems accessing your account, modifying your profile, changing your newsletter preferences, etc.; to show advertisers in aggregate form the demographic profile of our audience.

 **NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY**

Our Web server logs information about visitors that is not personally identifiable. Examples of this type of information include the type of Internet Browser you are using, the type of computer operating system you are using, and the domain name of the Web site from which you linked to our site or advertisement.

Also, when we collect personal data from you in a transaction, we may extract some information about that transaction in a non-identifiable format and combine it with other non-identifiable information. This information is used and analyzed only at an aggregate level to help us: understand trends and patterns; improve the content and design of the IT World Canada Web site; to enable our audit bureau to verify our claims of traffic to the site; and, to help advertisers and potential advertisers assess the suitability of the site for their advertising campaigns. This information is not reviewed at an individual level.

 **INFORMATION WE MAY PLACE AUTOMATICALLY ON YOUR COMPUTER’S HARD DRIVE**  
When you access some sections of ITWorldCanada.com or advertisements, we may store some information on your computer, in the form of a “Cookie”. A cookie is a piece of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your computer as a small text file. Cookies allow us to tailor the Web site content or advertisements to better match your interests and preferences. With most Internet Browsers, you can erase Cookies from your computer hard drive, block all Cookies, or receive a warning before a Cookie is stored. Please note, however, that blocking or disabling cookies will limit your access to non-restricted content sections, and erasing cookies will require that you re-register if you wish to access content in restricted sections of the site.

 **1X1 PIXEL TAGS**  
This site uses clear gifs pixel tags or other technologies to help manage our on-line advertising. These technologies may be in use in a number of locations throughout the site, and work in association with cookies. The information we collect and share through this technology is not personally identifiable. For more information about our ad-serving company or for your choices about not having this anonymous information used, please click here [www.doubleclick.net](http://www.doubleclick.net/)

 **LINKS TO NON-IT WORLD CANADA WEB SITES**  
While IT World Canada will seek to require third parties with whom it has agreements to follow appropriate privacy policies, we do not bear any responsibility for any actions or policies of such third parties.

This site contains links to other sites not owned or controlled by IT World Canada. IT World Canada is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

ITWorldCanada.com users should be aware that when they voluntarily disclose personal information (e.g., user name, e-mail address) in discussion forums that such information could be collected and used by others that do not follow our strict privacy guidelines and may result in unsolicited messages from other posters or parties.

 **THE 10 PRINCIPLES OF FAIR INFORMATION PRACTICES**

  *  **Accountability:** An organization is responsible for personal information under its custody and shall designate an individual or individuals who are accountable for the organization’s compliance with the following principles.
  *  **Identifying Purposes:** The purposes for which personal information is collected shall be identified by the organization at or before the time the information is collected.
  *  **Consent:** The knowledge and consent of the individual are required for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information, except where inappropriate.
  *  **Limiting Collection:** The collection of personal information shall be limited to that which is necessary for the purposes identified by the organization. Information shall be collected by fair and lawful means.
  *  **Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention:** Personal information shall not be used or disclosed for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the individual or as required by law. Personal information shall be retained only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes.
  *  **Accuracy:** Personal information shall be as accurate, complete and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used.
  *  **Safeguards:** Personal information shall be protected by security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information.
  *  **Openness:** An organization shall make readily available to individuals specific information about its policies and practices relating to the management of personal information.
  *  **Individual Access:** Upon request, an individual shall be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of his or her personal information, and shall be given access to that information. An individual shall be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate.
  *  **Challenging Compliance:** An individual shall be able to address a challenge concerning compliance with the above principles to the designated individual or individuals accountable for the organization’s compliance.
